Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajput.
I am an MBA Finance from Fund Family Financial Services and have been
working in the corporate sector for 13 years and today I am
presenting to you which will be the best plan
for you in the long term from all the companies like LC, SBI, Tata, Bilaya, Bajaj, IIC, STFC, Kotak etc.
where you have to pay premium for a limited period of 12 years
but you get guaranteed income for 20 years, 25 years, 30 years, then
where will be the best returns. All these
plans that I am telling you will give you 100% guaranteed
return. Here, once you have
purchased the policy, there will be no
change in your policy even if there are changes in the rate.
All the plans have insurance cover.
All the plans have
tax benefit in the income tax section ATC. The
income and maturity in all the plans will be tax free in 10D and 10D.
Loan will be available in all the plans.
So watch this video of mine completely
and if you like the video then you will
get my YouTube channel where you will get more
insurance cover. Come, let's see
all of my plans.  Before I explain the comparison of the plan, let me
do a small comparison with FDs
because most people in India
invest in FDs
because there is safety there. So the
comparison I have made here is the
rate of 5-year FD, as of today, the
SBI rate of 1st November 2023 is 6.5%.
If you get a 5-year FD done,
if you compare it with the guaranteed insurance plan, then
there you will get a return of 6.96, 6.7, even up to 6.8%. There will be
different returns in different plans. So here the
benefit that you are getting in the insurance cover, in the insurance policy, is
tax free, whereas in FD, there can be a
taxable FD. If you are
in the 30% income tax slab, then the
return
after tax from the FD will be only 4.55%. If you are
in the 20% income tax slab,
then the return in hand will be only 5.2%.
For you, if you fall in the 10% income tax slab, then
your FD
return will be 5.8% instead of 65%.
But here, whether you invest ₹1 lakh or 5
lakh, whether you fall in the 10% income
tax slab or the 30%
slab, you will get these returns
tax-free, that too with insurance cover.
If the customer dies in the FD,
what will you get? Suppose you have made an FD of 5 lakhs and if he dies, then
how much
% return will you get? You will get a little money along with the return, that
is, there is no insurance cover at all.
But in this plan, as you might have
seen in the comparison, your family will get the benefit
of an insurance cover of at least 50 lakhs or more,
that too for
30-35 years. If you paid the premium for 12 years,
waited for one year and took income for the next 30 years, that is, if the
policy is in force for 43 years, then
this rate of returns will be guaranteed for 43 years.  There
is no plan for 43 years in India right now which
gives you a written guarantee today in 2023
that your rate will remain fixed for 43 years, there will be
no increase or decrease, that too tax free. So
definitely look at this plan. Let's see how it works
and now let's compare long term
guaranteed income plans to see
which plan can give you more benefits.
I am doing this comparison at the age of 35 years
and I have made this plan on
1st November 2023, that is today.
Its rates can be more or less in the future. These are
plans of any company. Here I have
taken a premium of ₹ 1 lakh and have taken it for HNE customers
because the survival and maturity benefits on premiums above 5 lakhs can be
taxable, so you have taken premium up to 5 lakhs.
I have taken a plan of LIC
which has Dhanrekha plan.
Pay the premium for 15 years. The policy will run for 30 years. Now I have taken
Smart Platina Plus for
10 years.  To pay the premium, you have to
wait for one year, then you will get income for the next 25 years
and the money deposited will also be returned.
ICICI's Gift Pro plan has been taken,
when you have to pay the premium for 12 years, wait for one year
and you will get income for 25 years.
Then another option is taken that pay the premium for 12 years,
wait for one year, you will get income for 30 years and
later you will get the deposited money back.
ADFC's Sansh Plus is, pay for 12 years,
wait for one year, you will get income for 30 years. Tata's Fun
Guarantee Plus is, pay for 12 years, wait for 1 year, you will get
guaranteed income for 30 years and the deposited
money will be refunded. Similarly, Max's Swag
plan has been taken, where the
option of one year waiting period for 12 years is also taken.
Wait for 5 years after 12 years, if you get income for another 30 years, then
how much income will you get. Kotak's
Guaranteed Fund Builder plan has been taken, in
which the premium payment is for 10 years,
waiting for one year, you will get income for 25 years.  Bajaj has
Add Wealth Goal and Birla has Assured
Income Plus Plan, so we have compared all these plans
which give long term income
100% guaranteed, no bonus, nothing
related to share market. Now first of all let us
look at LIC's Dhan Rekha where a
35 year old customer pays premium for 15 years,
pays 55 lakhs and the maturity is at 30 years,
so what benefits will he get, if
he pays premium for 15 years, he will get a
maturity of 10 lakh 5000 in 15 years,
a guaranteed money back will come, then in the 20th
year also he will get 10500 guaranteed, then in the 25th year also he will get
105000 guaranteed and finally in the 10th year he will get a
guaranteed 1 crore 5400. 1
crore 5400 will be available as premium in the policy.
In this you have to pay 55 lakhs for 15 years
and all these benefits will be 100%
guaranteed. Now let us look at SBI's
plan Smart Platin  Plus Plus in which
you have to pay premium for 10 years, you have to
wait for one year, you will be deferred
and you will get 100% guaranteed income for 25 years,
so here you see that you
paid premium for 10 years,
you waited for 11 years for one year and from 12 years you will
start getting annual guaranteed income of Rs 464,750, 4647
for next 25 years and
in the end you will also get a maturity
of Rs 9647, you will also get this one maturity, it will be
tax free maturity
and in all these plans the insurance cover will
also be at least 10 times from the first day,
due to this whatever income you get will be
tax free, if you look at ICICI's Gift Pro, you have to pay
premium for 12 years, you have to
wait for 1 year, you will get only income for 25 years, if
not maturity then you will keep getting
guaranteed ₹ 335502 in your account every year for 25 years,
now if you are an
ICICI Bank employee  If you take another plan where you
pay premium for 12 years only, wait for one year only,
want to get income for 30 years and
want refund of the deposited money at maturity, then you will get an
income of Rs 679 150 for 30 years and in the end
you will get back all the deposited money of Rs 6679 150. In 12 years you are
getting an income of Rs 6 lakh on Rs 1 lakh, so
you will see a total of Rs 66 lakh here,
all this will be tax free. If you
compare it with SSE Plus ADC,
then in SSE Plus you will get an income of Rs 45000
and you will get refund of Rs
65000. If you compare it with TA, then you will get an
income of Rs 8650. Wait for 1 year on 12 years premium and
take income for 30 years, then
TA's Fetch Guarantee Plus will
give you an income of Rs 6 lakh 8650 every year and in the end
you will get refund of all the deposited money.  It goes
tax
free. Now if we look at the Swag plan of Max Life Insurance,
here the premium has to be paid for 12 years, one has to
wait for one year, if a
person takes income for 30 years, then he will get an income of ₹ 76000
and the money deposited will be refunded.
But if in Max's Swag, he takes a deferment of 5 years, that is, after
paying 12 years premium, he waits for 5 years, that is, if he
wants to take income from the age of 18, then he will get an
income of ₹ 92346. This 5 year waiting
period option is available in other companies as well,
in TA as well, in ADAC as well, in III as well.
So if you want to wait for 5 years, 3 years,
2 years, then
options are also given in different companies, so
you can take it accordingly. I have told you as a sample
that suppose you wait for
5 years in Max, then you will get an
income of ₹ 920000 every year for 30 years and at the end the
money deposited will be refunded.
Now let's talk.  In Kotak, there is an
option to pay for 10 years instead of 12 years. If you
wait for one year and take income for 25 years,
then the income will be Rs 486 540 and the
maturity will be Rs
5486 540. Talking about Bajaj Finance's
A Wealth Goal Plan, if you pay for 12 years and
wait for one year and take income for 30 years, then the
income will be Rs 6737 every year and at the end the
money paid will be refunded. And compare it with Without
Cash Income Plus, if you pay premium for 12 years
and wait for one year and take income for 25 years, then the
income will be Rs 8000 every year and the
maturity will also be Rs 76 lakh. Now in different plans,
you will see that someone's IR
is at 45, someone's is at 6.19 and someone's
IR is even at 6.88. If
you look at each one, one company has insurance of Rs 67 lakh
from the first day, and somewhere else  If there is insurance of Rs 55 lakh,
then there is insurance of Rs 3 lakh, then there is
insurance of Rs 70 lakh. Different
companies offer different insurance covers and
this insurance cover also increases with time.
So which plan will be better for you?
You can
look at it based on the income, the company, the claim settlement, the
premium payment term, the deficiency, the
insurance cover.
You can purchase the plan that is suitable for you.
I have told you the
comparison of what returns you will expect against a premium.
Friends, if I
summarize this finally, you will see
that according to your needs,
if you want to take a plan for a long time as a pension, as a retirement
or as a money back income, then according to
your needs, you
can take the benefit of the policy for a long time by paying the premium for 10 years or 12 years and you can get tax free income. There are
some questions that I want to leave for you:
which policy will provide you with a
limited premium payment term?  You may
pay premium for only five years, seven years
but you get guaranteed income for 25, 30 or 35 years. Is there
any such plan
where I get insurance cover which keeps increasing every year? Is there any
such plan
where whether I am 35 years old or 55 years
old, my income does not decrease, I get the
same income as a 35 year old person.
If instead of one year reference
period, I do not take a reference period of even one year or
take a reference period of two or three years, then which plan will
provide higher returns for me? By
doing a comparison, you will understand that suppose there
is a company, if a customer dies at the age of 14,
then the
amount it gives you is around Rs 64 lakh as
death benefit, whereas
another company provides one crore on death at the age of 14. So,
in which plan will you get the highest death benefit?
Which plan is such where I will
get insurance cover till the premium payment term? Which plan is like this?  Where
I will get insurance cover till the entire policy term is valid. Is there
any such plan where if I
die at the time when my income starts, then
my family members will continue to get the income
and the maturity premium that is going to come
during the policy term will also be given to them. Is there
any such plan where if my
proposer dies while paying the premium, then the
premium payment will be waived and the policy will provide
continuous benefit. Is there any such plan
where I can add such a feature
where if I die, then I will get the death benefit
immediately, the premium payment will be waived, the
income that is to come every year will start and
maturity will also be given. The answer to all these questions is
yes, you will get all the options
but to know which company's
plan will get you this,
you can whatsapp me on 2. If you want to buy a policy from me, then
you can
also find me on Quora.
You can write your question there and I will
provide you the answer there as well. If you
liked the video before leaving, Anil Raj
Triple S is my friend.